<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Derma</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="nav_header_title">Android Studio</string>
    <string name="nav_header_subtitle">android.studio@android.com</string>
    <string name="nav_header_desc">Navigation header</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="logo_image">Logo Image</string>
    <string name="title_activity_main">MainActivity</string>

    <string name="v_info">Vitiligo is a long-term problem in which growing patches of skin lose their color The patches appear when melanocytes within the skin die off. Melanocytes are the cells responsible for producing the skin pigment, melanin, which gives skin its color and protects it from the sun\'s UV rays,The total area of skin that can  be affected by vitiligo varies between individuals.</string>
    <string name="v_causes">The exact cause of vitiligo is unknown, although most experts believe that it is an autoimmune condition in which the body\'s immune system mistakenly attacks ,It is also possible that one or more genes may make a person more likely to get the disorder.</string>
    <string name="v_symp">People who develop vitiligo usually first notice white patches or spots (depigmentation) on their skin. The skin remains of normal texture, though some people experience itching in areas where depigmentation is occurring. The white patches are more obvious in sun-exposed areas, including the hands, feet, arms, face, and lips,The armpits and groin Around the mouth,Eyes,Nostrils,Navel,Genitals,Rectal areas.In addition to white patches on the skin, some people with vitiligo may experience white hair growing in on the scalp, eyelashes, eyebrows, and beard.</string>
    <string name="v_treat">The American Academy of Dermatology (AAD) describe vitiligo as \"more than a cosmetic problem.\" It is a health issue that needs medical attention.\nSome medical treatments can reduce the severity of the condition, but it can be difficult to cure.\n1-The AAD recommend using a sunscreen, because the lighter patches of skin are especially sensitive to sunlight and they can burn easily.\n2- Phototherapy with UVB light\nExposure to ultraviolet B (UVB) lamps is a common treatment option.\n3-Removing the color from other areas so they match the white patches.\n4-Surgical treatments include:\nSkin grafts from a person\'s own tissues. The doctor takes skin from one area of a patient\'s body and attaches it to another area. This is sometimes used for people with small patches of vitiligo</string>
    <string name="v_extra">In most cases, the affected areas remain discolored for the rest of the person\'s life.It is hard to predict whether the patches will spread, and by how much.The spread might take weeks, or the patches might remain stable for months or years.\npopulation:\nIt appears to affect between 0.5 and 2 percent of people and. It can affect people of any age, gender, or ethnic group.most people who have vitiligo will develop the condition prior to age 40 about half develop it before age 20.\nIs vitiligo contagious?\nVitligo is not contagious it dose not spreed from person to person not caused by germ , bacteria or virus that can spread like flu or commen cold touching discolored skin does not spread it on persons own body or to onther person\npattern of vitiligo:\n1-Focal pattern: the depigmentation is limited only to a few areas.\n2-segmental vitiligo:Some people develop depigmented patches on only one side of their bodies\n3-generalized vitiligo:most people who have vitiligo, depigmentation occurs on different parts of the body, in a bilateral pattern\n</string>

    <string name="p_intro">Psoriasis is a long-lasting autoimmune disease characterized by patches of abnormal skin. These skin patches are typically red, dry, itchy, and scaly. On people with darker skin the patches may be purple in color. Psoriasis varies in severity from small, localized patches to complete body coverage. Injury to the skin can trigger psoriatic skin changes at that spot, which is known as the Koebner phenomenon.\n\nThere are five main types of psoriasis: plaque, guttate, inverse, pustular, and erythrodermic. Plaque psoriasis, also known as psoriasis vulgaris, makes up about 90 percent of cases.It typically presents as red patches with white scales on top areas of the body most commonly affected are the back of the forearms, shins, navel area, and scalp. Guttate psoriasis has drop-shaped lesions. Pustular psoriasis presents as small non-infectious pus-filled blisters. Inverse psoriasis forms red patches in skin folds. Erythrodermic psoriasis occurs when the rash becomes very widespread, and can develop from any of the other types. Fingernails and toenails are affected in most people with psoriasis at some point in time. This may include pits in the nails or changes in nail color.\n\nPsoriasis is generally thought to be a genetic disease that is triggered by environmental factors. In twin studies, identical twins are three times more likely to be affected compared to non-identical twins. This suggests that genetic factors predispose to psoriasis. Symptoms often worsen during winter and with certain medications, such as beta blockers or NSAIDs. Infections and psychological stress can also play a role. Psoriasis is not contagious. The underlying mechanism involves the immune system reacting to skin cells. Diagnosis is typically based on the signs and symptoms.</string>
    <string name="p_causes">The exact cause of psoriasis isn\’t fully understood, but scientists believe psoriasis is the result of several factors, including genetics, environmental factors, and the immune system.\nThe cause related to an immune system problem with T-cells and other white blood cells, called neutrophils, in your body.\nT-cells normally travel through the body to defend against foreign substances, such as viruses or bacteria, but if you have psoriasis, the T-cells attack healthy skin cells by mistake, as if to heal a wound or to fight an infection.\nOveractive T-cells also trigger increased production of healthy skin cells, more T-cells and other white blood cells, especially neutrophils. These travel into the skin causing redness and sometimes pus in pustular lesions. Dilated blood vessels in psoriasis-affected areas create warmth and redness in the skin lesions.\nThe process becomes an ongoing cycle in which new skin cells move to the outermost layer of skin too quickly — in days rather than weeks. Skin cells build up in thick, scaly patches on the skin\'s surface, continuing until treatment stops the cycle.\nJust what causes T-cells to malfunction in people with psoriasis isn\'t entirely clear. Researchers believe both genetics and environmental factors play a role.</string>
    <string name="p_symp">The signs and symptoms of psoriasis can vary depending on the type of psoriasis you have. The 5 most common symptoms of psoriasis include:\n\nRashes or patches of red, inflamed skin often covered with loose, silver-colored scales. In severe cases, the plaques will grow and merge into one another, covering large areas.\nItchy, painful skin that can crack or bleed.\nSmall areas of bleeding where the involved skin is scratched.\nProblems with your fingernails and toenails, including discoloration and pitting. The nails may also begin to crumble or detach from the nail bed.\nScaly plaques on the scalp.\nPsoriasis can also be associated with psoriatic arthritis, which causes achy, swollen joints. Between 10% and 30% of people with psoriasis also have this painful joint condition.</string>
    <string name="p_treatment">There is no cure for psoriasis; however, various treatments can help control the symptoms. These treatments include steroid creams, vitamin D3 cream, ultraviolet light and immune system suppressing medications, such as methotrexate about 75 percent of cases can be managed with creams alone.\n\n                                \nTopical treatments\nCreams and ointments applied directly to the skin can be helpful for reducing mild to moderate psoriasis.\nTopical psoriasis treatments include:\n\ttopical corticosteroids\n\ttopical retinoid\n\tanthralin\n\tvitamin D analogues\n\tsalicylic acid\n\tmoisturizer\nSystemic medications\nPeople with moderate to severe psoriasis, and those who haven\'t responded well to other treatment types, may need to use oral or injected medications. Many of these medications have severe side effects. Doctors usually prescribe them for short periods of time.\nThese medications include:\n\tmethotrexate\n\tcyclosporine (Sandimmune)\n\tbiologics\n\tretinoid\n\nLight therapy\nThis psoriasis treatment uses ultraviolet (UV) or natural light. Sunlight kills the overactive white blood cells that are attacking healthy skin cells and causing the rapid cell growth. Both UVA and UVB light may be helpful in reducing symptoms of mild to moderate psoriasis.\nMost people with moderate to severe psoriasis will benefit from a combination of treatments. This type of therapy uses more than one of the treatment types to reduce symptoms. Some people may use the same treatment their entire lives. Others may need to change treatments occasionally if their skin stops responding to what they\'re using.\nMedication for psoriasis\nIf you have moderate to severe psoriasis \u2014 or if psoriasis stops responding to other treatments \u2014 your doctor may consider an oral or injected medication.\nThe most common oral and injected medications used to treat psoriasis include:\nBiologics\nThis class of medications alters your immune system and prevents interactions between your immune system and inflammatory pathways. These medications are injected or given through intravenous (IV) infusion.\nRetinoids\nRetinoids reduce skin cell production. Once you stop using them, symptoms of psoriasis will likely return. \nSide effects include hair loss and lip inflammation. \n People who are pregnant or may become pregnant within the next three years shouldn\'t take retinoids because of the risk of possible birth defects.\nCyclosporine\nCyclosporine (Sandimmune) prevents the immune system\'s response. This can ease symptoms of psoriasis. It also means you have a weakened immune system, so you may become sick more easily. Side effects include kidney problems and high blood pressure.\nMethotrexate\nLike cyclosporine, methotrexate suppresses the immune system.\nIt may cause fewer side effects when used in low doses. It can cause serious side effects in the long term. Serious side effects include liver damage and reduced production of red and white blood cells.\n</string>
    <string name="p_extra">The Genetic Link\nIf you have psoriasis, it\'s possible that someone in your family may have had it too. That\'s because there appears to be a genetic link for psoriasis.\nOne out of 3 people with psoriasis reports having a relative with the disease. And researchers say that up to 10% of the general population may inherit one or more genes that predispose them to psoriasis, though only 2% to 3% of people with the gene actually develop the disease.\nEnvironmental Triggers\nCertain environmental factors may trigger the psoriasis genes, causing the disease to become active. These environmental triggers vary from person to person, and what causes psoriasis to develop in one person may have no effect on someone else.\nSome triggers known to impact psoriasis symptoms include:\n\tStress\n\tInjury to skin (cuts, scrapes, bug bites, severe sunburns)\n\tInfection (such as strep throat or thrush)\n\tCertain medications (including lithium, antimalarial, quinidine, indomethacin)\n\nPsoriasis and Comorbidities\nWhen a person has two or more diseases at one time, these are called \u201Ccomorbidities\".\nComorbidities associated with psoriasis include other immune conditions such as psoriatic arthritis and Crohn\'s disease.\nIt\'s important to keep your doctor informed about any symptoms you may be having so the two of you can decide how to possibly avoid or manage comorbidities.\nOther Comorbidities\nPsoriasis has been linked to other health conditions. Psoriasis is not thought to cause these conditions or vice versa. Patients with psoriasis have a greater likelihood of being diagnosed with the following conditions:\n\tPsoriatic Arthritis\n\tType 2 diabetes\n\tCardiovascular disease\n\tHigh blood pressure\n\tCrohn\'s Disease\n\tHigh cholesterol\n\tDepression\n\tUlcerative colitis\nTalk to your doctor if you have any of these health conditions along with signs and symptoms of psoriasis. It\'s important to tell your doctor about other symptoms, because each medical condition needs to be treated separately and may require different medication.\nFoods That Might Cause Psoriasis Flare-ups\nResearch has yet to confirm a definitive link between diet and psoriasis flare-ups, but some people say that eliminating certain foods and drinks offers relief from symptoms.\nSome people with psoriasis are convinced that what they eat affects how their skin looks and feels.\n\tAlcohol \u201CFirst and foremost, stop drinking. Here\'s why: Alcohol opens the blood vessels in the skin. When your blood vessels are dilated, white blood cells, including the T-cells that are believed to be responsible for psoriasis, can sneak into the outer layers of your skin more easily \u2014 and you don\'t need to be inviting more T-cells. \u201CYour psoriasis symptoms may worsen even if you\'re a light to moderate alcohol user.\u201D \n\tJunk Food Psoriasis is an inflammatory condition, and junk foods tend to be high in saturated and trans fats and refined starches and sugars, all of which can promote inflammation\n\tRed Meat Red meats contain a polyunsaturated fat called arachidonic acid. \u201CThis type of fat can worsen psoriasis symptoms because it can easily be converted into inflammatory compounds,\u201D \n\tDairy Products Like red meat, dairy products also contain the natural inflammatory arachidonic acid. \u201CCow\'s milk is one of the biggest culprits, because it also contains the protein casein, which has been linked to inflammation. Egg yolks, too, are high in arachidonic acid, so consider nixing them from your diet.\n\tNightshade Plants Some people report that consuming plants from the \u201Cnightshade family\u201D \u2014 which includes peppers, white potatoes, eggplant, and tomatoes \u2014 exacerbates their psoriasis. These vegetables contain solanine, a chemical compound that has been shown to trigger pain in some people. \u201CCertain patients believe that if you avoid these vegetables, you decrease your symptoms.\u201D \n\tCitrus Fruits Sometimes an allergic reaction can cause psoriasis to flare. Citrus fruits, such as grapefruit, oranges, lemons, and limes, are a common allergen. See if eliminating them from your diet improves your skin. This goes for their derivatives as well, such as lemonade and grapefruit juice.\n\tGluten This protein is found in some grass-related grains, including rye, wheat, and barley. Researchers in Portugal found that psoriasis symptoms in some people with a gluten sensitivity improved after they began avoiding gluten. Studies are ongoing, but the idea of psoriasis patients benefiting from a gluten-free diet is still controversial\n\tCondiments Some people with psoriasis find condiments and spices to be their enemy. The ones that seem to cause the most trouble for people with psoriasis are pimento, cinnamon, curry, vinegar, mayo, paprika, Tabasco sauce, and ketchup.</string>
</resources>
